杰森 · 兰斯托夫: 现在，我们看到的是,
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: And so,
now what we've got here,
当这个结果组件加载时，它会收到一个名字道具。
is when this result component loads,
it's gonna receive a name prop.
在安装时，它将运行这个 useQuery 和
Upon mounting,
it's going to run this useQuery and
Usequery 将决定什么显示。
that useQuery will determine what display.
因此，我们要么显示加载阶段，要么显示错误阶段，要么显示结果，或者
So we'll either show a loading stage,
an error stage, or the results, or
如果没有结果，就是一个空的状态。
an empty state if there's no results.
所以让我们继续运行它，看看会发生什么。
So let's go ahead and
run it and see what happens.
我们要用 netlify dev。
We're gonna use netlify dev.
所以要使用它，我们必须导入它,
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: So
to use it we are gonna have to import it,
我们来看看结果吧。
so let's grab results and results.
然后你可以把这个放在这里。
And then you can drop this in here.
它需要一个名字，所以我们现在只需要一个硬编码，我们就叫它 rick。
And it needs a name, so let's just
hard code one for now, we'll say rick.
杰森 · 兰斯托夫: 我们有一个问题，这个问题是我们安装的
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: And we've got
an issue, and that issue is we installed
但我们实际上并没有配置它。
the Apollo plugin, but
we didn't actually configure it.
所以在我们的盖茨比配置中，我们将-Jason Lengstorf: set
So in our gatsby config, we're going to-
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: set
模块化，导出，然后我们设置插件。
up module.exports and
then we will set up our plugins.
我们要解决盖茨比插件阿波罗
And we're gonna resolve
gatsby-plugin-apollo, and
对于我们的选择，我们要设置一个 uri。
for our options, we're gonna set a uri.
这个 uri 就是 rickandmortyapi.com/graphql。
And that uri is going to be
the rickandmortyapi.com/graphql.
我们正在做的是，我们正在告诉阿波罗建立一个客户。
And what we're doing is,
we're telling Apollo to set up a client.
我们想要成立的客户,
And the client that we wanna set up,
将尝试连接到一个 GraphQL 端点进行查询。
is going to try to attach to a GraphQL
endpoint to make queries against.
所以我们这么做,
So the way that we're doing this,
我们用了 gatsby-plugin-apollo 的助手。
we're using a helper in
the gatsby-plugin-apollo.
这样我们就不用设置供应商
So that we don't have to
set up the provider and
配置客户端。
mess with getting the client configured.
只有在最幸福的路上才行得通,
This is only gonna work
in the happiest of paths,
如果你做什么自定义，中间件之类的东西。
if you're doing anything custom,
middleware, anything like that.
您可能会发现自己必须手动配置 Apollo 客户机。
You'll probably find yourself having to
manually configure the Apollo client.
但是对于你的 GraphQL 端点非常简单的例子,
But for simple examples where your GraphQL
endpoint is pretty straightforward,
你没有做任何交叉起源的事情。
you're not doing any kind
of cross origin stuff.
你会发现这是一个非常好的方式，非常快速地设置
You're gonna find that this is a really
nice way to very quickly set up
Graphql 客户机。
the GraphQL client.
现在这个配置好了，我们应该可以重新启动它了,
So now that this is configured,
we should be able to start it again,
现在还有一个 Apollo 的客户要竞争。
and now it'll actually have
a Apollo client to run against.
让我们做 netlify dev。
Let's do netlify dev.
杰森 · 兰斯托夫: 好的。
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: Okay.
杰森 · 兰斯托夫: 好吧，那么-杰森 · 兰斯托夫: 我们还不错
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: All right, so-
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: We're kind of okay
但是出了点问题，因为我们应该有结果。
here, but something went wrong,
because we should have results.
那么为什么它不喜欢我们的结果呢？
So why doesn't it like our results?
杰森 · 兰斯托夫: 我们正在得到它们，所以
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: And
we're getting them, so
这是我最喜欢的黑客，当你做客户端的东西。
this is my favorite hack when
you're doing client-side stuff.
你可以进入网络选项卡，看看发生了什么，等等
Is you can go to the Network tab and
see what's happening, and so
我们知道我们得到了数据。
we know we're getting data.
所以错误在我的代码中，而不是网络的问题。
So the error is in my code,
not a problem with the network.
所以我们可以回顾一下我们的研究结果，看看我们漏掉了什么。
So we can go back and look at our results,
and figure out what was missed.
Jason Lengstorf: 如果我们有数据，我们有数据字符。
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: So we've got if we've
got data, and we've got data characters.
杰森 · 兰斯托夫: 但我们需要结果的长度,
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: But
we need the results length,
不是字符的长度，所以这是我。
not the characters length, so that is me.
我们走吧。
Hey, there we go.
所以我们现在可以看到的是我们正在做一个搜索，并且
So what we can see now is that
we are doing a search, and
我们正在寻找我们想要的东西。
we're getting a search for what we want.
好了，一切顺利，我们去找瑞克，去找莫蒂。
Okay, this is all good, so let's search
for Rick, let's search for Morty.
好吧，我们还没有取出任何东西，我们已经把名字硬编码了。
Okay, so we're not pulling anything
out yet, we've hard-coded our name.
所以我们最不想做的就是,
So the last thing that we wanna do here,
就是从州里提取那个问题，如果我们在本地做的话。
is extract that query from the state,
if we're doing it locally.
或者如果我们和它有联系的话。
Or from the Path if we're
being linked to it.
确保我们真的在寻找我们想要寻找的东西,
And make sure that we're actually
searching for what we wanna search for,
而不是什么硬编码。
and not what's hard-coded.
为了做到这一点，我们将打开我们的搜索组件,
So to do that, we're going to
open up our search component,
我需要重命名为搜索。
I need to rename that to Search.
在里面我们要把它变成一个完整的函数,
And inside of it we are going to
turn this into a full function,
这样我们就可以对其进行查询管理。
so that we can do some
query management in it.
我们要把查询从这个地方拿出来。
And we're gonna get the query
out of the location.
所以盖茨比要写进每一页的东西
So something that Gatsby is
gonna pass into every page, and
再说一遍，这只是几页。
again this is only for pages.
所以任何在《了不起的盖茨比》中创造页面的动作,
So anything that's created with
the Create Page action in Gatsby,
也就是 pages 目录中的任何内容。
which is anything in the pages directory.
或者任何使用盖茨比操作创建页面的模板。
Or anything that's created as a template
using like Gatsby actions Create Page.
这个位置会以一个对象的形式出现，给我们一些关于这个位置的元数据
The location is gonna come in as an object
that gives us some metadata about where
是的。
we are.
在这个案子里我们想要的是,
And what we want
specifically in this case,
我们想知道地点，国家。
is we want to get the location.state.
如果已经设置好了，我们希望得到查询，所以 location.state.query。
And if that's set, we wanna get the query
out of it, so location.state.query.
如果没有设置，那么我们可以跳下去
And if that's not set,
then we can jump down and
让我们找到路径，路径名。
say let's get the location.pathname.
所以 location.pathname 就像 Search / Morty。
So the location.pathname is
gonna be like Search /Morty.
所以我们可以替换，我们再一次进入了正则表达式的领域。
So we can replace, and again we're
getting into regular expression land.
所以任何开始搜索的东西，我们都要-
So anything starting with search,
we are going to-
Jason Lengstorf: 删除 / search 和
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: remove the /search and
在那之后，我们就什么都不用了。
the \ after that, and
we will replace it with nothing.
如果这不起作用，我们将它设置为空字符串。
And if that doesn't work,
we will set it to be an empty string.
然后为了得到名字，我们要做一个 query.replace。
And then to get the name,
we're going to do a query.replace.
我们只想用连字符
And we just wanna take any hyphens and
用空格字符替换它们。
replace them with a space character.
所以我们在这里使用正则表达式。
And so
we're using regular expressions here.
所以任何连字符，加号意味着一个或多个，所以我们要找一个或多个连字符。
So any hyphen, the plus means one or more,
so we're looking for one or more hyphens.
然后我们把它们压缩成一个空格字符。
And then we'll collapse those down
into a single space character.
这意味着我们现在有了一个名字
That means that we have a name now, and
这也意味着我们可以提供一些有用的信息。
it also means that we can show
a little more helpful information.
让我们开始，我们引用这个，如果名字设置好了。
So let's start, we'll quote this and
we'll say that if the name is set.
我们要说的是显示“”和
We're going to say Showing results for
"" and
这需要一个模板文字。
that's gonna need to
be a template literal.
否则，显示搜索里克和莫蒂。
Otherwise, show Search for Rick and Morty.
因此，首先它应该告诉我们当前的搜索查询是正确的
So first it should show us what our
current Search query is right in
标题。
the headline.
接下来，我们要说如果我们
Next, we're going to say if we have
一个名字，然后显示结果。
a name, then show the results.
杰森 · 兰斯托夫: 我们在这里应该看到的是,
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: And so
what we should see here,
现在它给我们显示了 morty 的结果，它会从这里拉出来。
is now it's showing us results for
morty and it will pull that from here.
所以如果我再做一次搜索，假设是外星人，它会载入外星人。
So if I do another search,
let's say alien, it loads aliens.
如果我搜索 Rick 就会找到 Rick。
And if I search for
rick, it pulls up Rick.
如果我拿这样的东西
And then if I take something like this,
and
我把它直接输入网址，它会搜索裁判。
I throw it right into the URL,
it will search for Adjudicator.
所以我们现在可以通过更新 URL 来搜索内容。
So we can now search for
things by updating the URL.
我们可以分享这些链接，有人可以点击它
We can share these links around and
someone could click it and
看到那些结果了吗。
see those results.
所有这些都是通过前端使用阿波罗来完成的
And all of that's done by using
Apollo on the frontend, and
然后在盖茨比设立客户路线。
then setting up client routes in Gatsby.
处理所有的路由和
To handle all of the routing and
确保事情按计划进行。
making sure that things end up
where they're supposed to be.